Jodi Tivis

Fort Collins, CO 80525 | Phone: 719.355.9114 | Email: joditivis@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/jodi-tivis | GitHub: github.com/joditivis |

Portfolio: https://joditivis.github.io/joditivis/

Summary

Front-End Web Developer with a focus and interest in creating a visually rich and appealing experience for users. Known as a determined creative, and strong team player, with a willingness to complete whatever task is placed ahead. Excited to combine my technical skill set with my background developing exceptional visual content to create one of a kind user experiences.

Technical Skills

HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Materialize, JavaScript, jQuery, Firebase, Node JS, MySQL, Express, Sequelize, Handlebars, Mongo DB, Mongoose, and React JS.

Work Experience

Web Design & Development | King Creative Marketing + Design2020Arkansas Career Pathways | Squarespace & custom CSS/JSFort Collins, CO

Personal Assistant | Hilary Silver International2018 - 2020Social Media manager/content creator, video editor, event photographerDenver, CO

Photographer | Freelance 2012 - 2020 https://joditivisphotography.pixieset.com/ Fort Collins, CO

Photographed a variety of events.

Projects

U-Travel | https://u-travel-dt.herokuapp.com/ | https://github.com/Nicole103/U-Travel

University of Arkansas Workforce Alliance | Squarespace & custom CSS/JS

Project Summary: U-Travel is a MERN app that allows users a fun way to plan for vacation. Search flights and hotels, save a packing list, add all trip expenses and keep track of how much they have saved.

Personal Responsibilities: Implemented user authentication using Passport.js, as well as ReactStrap to create a fun, dynamic, and cohesive UI/UX.

Tools/Languages used: HTML5, CSS3, ReactStrap, React.js, JavaScript, Passport.js, Express, Node JS MongoDB, Mongoose, Weather API, Amadeus API

Restaurant Finder | https://best-restaurant.herokuapp.com/ | https://github.com/joditivis/Project2

Project Summary: An 11 question survey takes in a user's location, cravings, dietary restrictions, favorites and more, to help find a restaurant in their area or town they are visiting.

Personal Responsibilities: Web page UI/UX

Tools/Languages used: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Node JS, Express, Handlebars, MySQL, and Sequelize ORM

Gif-ting | stacyholtz6.github.io/Gif-ting/ | github.com/joditivis/Gif-ting

Project Summary: Gif-ting allows users to improve on holiday shopping organization and gives users gif(t) ideas for each person they are shopping for.

Personal Responsibilities: Using the GIPHY API, generated a GIF based on each person's word description, as well as a gift generator to generate gift ideas relevant to each person's keyword.

Tools/Languages used: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, Slick Carousel, Firebase, Etsy API, GIPHY API

Education

Bootcamp Certificate: University of Denver | Denver, CO | September 2019 - March 2020 A six-month intensive web development program focused on gaining technical skills in the most up-to-date developer languages.